## **Keunwoo Park**

kwpark.io

keunwoopark.524@gmail.com

last updated: August 2023

I lead the software product team at Ordinary Magic Corp., a company based in South Korea, making toys for infants and toddlers under the Peekaby brand. We build software products to deliver content about toys and intelligent tools to improve the playing experiences.

## **Employment Experience**

Ordinary Magic Corp. April. 2023 - Present

Software Product Team Leader

IUMSOCIOUS (Online dating startup)

Jul. 2012 - Dec. 2012

Full-stack Web Developer

### Education

KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2017 - Aug 2023

Ph.D. Computer Science

**Human-Computer Interaction Lab** 

Adviser: Geehyuk Lee

KAIST, School of Computing

Mar 2015 - Feb 2017

M.S. Computer Science

**Human-Computer Interaction Lab** 

Adviser: Geehyuk Lee

**KAIST** Feb 2009 - Feb 2015

**B.S.** Mechanical Engineering

**B.S.** Computer Science

## **Publications**

#### Conferences

"FoolProofJoint: Reducing Assembly Errors of Laser Cut 3D Models by Means of Custom Joint Patterns"

**Keunwoo Park**, Conrad Lempert, Muhammad Abdullah, Shohei Katakura, Jotaro Shigeyama, Thijs Roumen, and Patrick Baudisch

Proceedings of the 2022 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. ACM, 2022.

"SGToolkit: An Interactive Gesture Authoring Toolkit for Embodied Conversational Agents."

Youngwoo Yoon\*, **Keunwoo Park**\*, Minsu Jang, Jaehong Kim, and Geehyuk Lee. *Proceedings of the 34th Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*. 2021.

"AtaTouch: Robust Finger Pinch Detection for a VR Controller Using RF Return Loss." Daehwa Kim, **Keunwoo Park**, and Geehyuk Lee.

Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. ACM, 2020.

(Honorable Mention Award)

"DeepFisheye: Near-Surface Multi-Finger Tracking Technology Using Fisheye Camera." **Keunwoo Park**, Sunbum Kim, Youngwoo Yoon, Tae-Kyun Kim, and Geehyuk Lee. *Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology*. 2020.

"OddEyeCam: A Sensing Technique for Body-Centric Peephole Interaction using WFoV RGB and NFoV Depth Cameras."

Daehwa Kim, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee.

Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology. 2020.

"FS-Pad: Video Game Interactions with a Force Feedback Gamepad."

Youngbo Aram Shim, **Keunwoo Park**, Sangyoon Lee, Jeongmin Son, Taeyun Woo, and Geehyuk Lee.

Proceedings of the 33rd Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology. 2020.

"MagTouch: Robust Finger Identification for a Smartwatch Using a Magnet Ring and a Built-in Magnetometer."

Keunwoo Park, Daehwa Kim, Seongkook Heo, and Geehyuk Lee.

Proceedings of the 2020 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. ACM, 2020.

"Using Poke Stimuli to Improve a 3x3 Watch-back Tactile Display."

Youngbo Aram Shim, Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee.

Proceedings of the 21st International Conference on Human-Computer Interaction with Mobile Devices and Services. ACM, 2019.

(Honorable Mention Award)

"Designing Touch Gestures Using the Space around the Smartwatch as Continuous Input Space."

Jaehyun Han, Sunggeun Ahn, **Keunwoo Park**, and Geehyuk Lee. *Proceedings of the 2017 ACM International Conference on Interactive Surfaces and Spaces*. ACM, 2017.

#### **Journals**

"Evaluation of edge-based interaction on a square smartwatch." Sunggeun Ahn, Jaeyeon Lee, **Keunwoo Park**, and Geehyuk Lee. *International Journal of Human-Computer Studies 109* (2018): 68-78.

#### **Posters**

"FingMag: Finger Identification Method for Smartwatch."

Keunwoo Park, and Geehyuk Lee.

Extended Abstracts of the 2019 CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems. ACM, 2019.

"Touch180: Finger Identification on Mobile Touchscreen using Fisheye Camera and Convolutional Neural Network."

Insu Kim, **Keunwoo Park**, Youngwoo Yoon, and Geehyuk Lee.

The 31st Annual ACM Symposium on User Interface Software and Technology Adjunct Proceedings. ACM, 2018.

## Research Experiences

Research Intern at Hasso Plattner Institute (HPI) with Prof. Patrick Baudisch

Apr. 2021 - Nov. 2021

#### **Awards**

NAVER Ph.D. Fellowship Awards

2020

ACM UIST Student Innovation Contest. People's Choice

2017

#### **Academic Services**

Student Volunteer UIST 2016

Paper Reviewer CHI 2021, UIST 2020, Augmented Human 2020

# **Teaching Experience**

Teaching Assistant, KAIST Spring 2019
Introduction to Human-Computer Interaction

(Outstanding TA Award)

Teaching Assistant, KAIST Spring 2018

Introduction to Human-Computer Interaction